<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco Small Business Router Password Disclosure Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20140305-rpd</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-03-05T14:36:52</Date><Description>Initial public release</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-03-05T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-03-05T14:36:52</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">A
vulnerability in the web management interface of the
Cisco RV110W Wireless-N VPN Firewall, the Cisco RV215W Wireless-N VPN
Router, and the Cisco CVR100W Wireless-N VPN Router
could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to gain administrative-level access to the web management interface of the affected device.



The vulnerability is due to improper handling of authentication requests by the web framework. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by intercepting, modifying and resubmitting an authentication request. Successful exploitation of this vulnerability could give an attacker administrative-level access to the web-based administration interface on the affected device.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. There are currently no known workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability.
This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd["{{http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd}}"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd["{{http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd}}"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd</URL><Description>Cisco Small Business Router Password Disclosure Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=33019</URL><Description>Cisco Small Business Router Password Disclosure Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-183632">Cisco Small Business RV Series Router Firmware 1.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-183634">Cisco Small Business RV Series Router Firmware 1.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-183636">Cisco Small Business RV Series Router Firmware 1.2 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Small Business Router Password Disclosure Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCul94527</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A
vulnerability in the web management interface of the
Cisco RV110W Wireless-N VPN Firewall, the Cisco RV215W Wireless-N VPN
Router, and the Cisco CVR100W Wireless-N VPN Router
could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to gain
administrative-level access to the web management interface of the affected device.



The vulnerability is due to improper handling of authentication
requests by the web framework. An attacker could exploit this
vulnerability by intercepting, modifying, and resubmitting an
authentication request. Successful exploitation of this vulnerability
would give an attacker administrative-level access to the web-based
administration interface on the affected device.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-0683</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-183632</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-183634</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-183636</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may allow an attacker to gain full control of the affected device.  An attacker with full administrative access to the device can configure all the settings of the router through the web-based administration user interface.
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>10.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>8.3</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There are no known workarounds available at this time.</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140305-rpd</URL><Description>Cisco Small Business Router Password Disclosure Vulnerability</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>