<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>ciscosa-20140716-cm</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.1</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-07-16T14:31:19</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2014-07-18T17:55:37</Date><Description>Added fixed version information in the Vulnerable Products section.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-07-16T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-07-18T17:55:37</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the web server used in multiple Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway products could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to exploit a buffer overflow and cause arbitrary code execution.



The vulnerability is due to incorrect input validation for HTTP requests. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted HTTP request to the affected device. Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are not available.



This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following email addresses:

    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    fulldisclosure@seclists.org 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm</URL><Description>Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=34895</URL><Description>Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201002">Cisco Model DPQ3925 8x4 DOCSIS 3.0 Wireless Residential Gateway with EDVA 5.5.2</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCup40808</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the web server used in multiple Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway products could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to exploit a buffer overflow and cause arbitrary code execution.



The vulnerability is due to incorrect input validation for HTTP requests. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a specially crafted HTTP request to the affected device. Successful exploitation could allow the attacker to crash the web server and execute arbitrary code with elevated privileges on the affected device.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-3306</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-201002</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may cause the embedded web server to crash and allow the attacker to inject arbitrary commands and execute arbitrary code with elevated privileges.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>10.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>7.8</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:POC/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There are currently no known workarounds available for this vulnerability.</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ciscosa-20140716-cm</URL><Description>Cisco Wireless Residential Gateway Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>