<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Wi-Fi Protected Setup PIN Brute Force Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Response</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sr-20120111-wps</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>4.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2012-01-11T16:50:59</Date><Description>Corrected text mistakes in researcher's name.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.0</Number><Date>2012-01-18T18:14:16</Date><Description>Updated information for the Cisco WRP400.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>3.0</Number><Date>2012-01-27T22:18:41</Date><Description>Updated text for clarity. Updated the Cisco UC320W WPS Disable status to Yes due to release of DisableWPS.pmf. Added Cable and DSL access products currently under investigation. Added a link to Linksys product documentation.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>4.0</Number><Date>2012-02-29T20:15:55</Date><Description>Updated the Can the WPS feature be permanently disabled? column of the table in the "Vulnerable Products" section for WAP4410N: changed from Yes to No. PSIRT would like to thank Bill Sanderson for pointing out this document error. Corrected the "Fixed Software" section to include the full product name of the WAP4410N.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2012-01-11T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2012-02-29T20:15:55</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="1">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes></cvrfdoc>