<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco IronPort Appliances Telnet Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20120126-ironport</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>2.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.3</Number><Date>2012-02-08T15:20:29</Date><Description>Updated advisory to fix minor HTML formatting issue.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.4</Number><Date>2012-07-14T10:51:28</Date><Description>Updated meta-tags for Affected Products.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.0</Number><Date>2014-10-16T13:40:20</Date><Description>Added important information about Cisco WSA.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2012-01-26T17:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-12-08T21:21:32</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco AsyncOS Software for Cisco Web Security Appliance (WSA), Cisco Email Security Appliance (ESA), and Cisco Content Security Management Appliance (SMA) contain a vulnerability that may allow a remote, unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code with elevated privileges. 



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are available. 



Note: This security advisory has been updated to include important information about Cisco WSA



This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport</URL><Description>Cisco IronPort Appliances Telnet Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120126-ironport</URL><Description>Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Cisco IronPort Appliances Telnet Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117985">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliance 7.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117987">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliance 7.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117989">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliance 7.2 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117991">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliance 7.3 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117993">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliance 7.5 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117995">Cisco IronPort Security Management Appliance 7.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117997">Cisco IronPort Security Management Appliance 7.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-117999">Cisco IronPort Security Management Appliance 7.2 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-118001">Cisco IronPort Security Management Appliance 7.3 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Ironport BSD telnetd command execution vulnerability</Title><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Cisco IronPort Email Security Appliances (ESA) and Cisco IronPort Security Management Appliances (SMA) contain a vulnerability that may allow a remote, unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code with elevated privileges. 

 

Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are available.


</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2011-4862</CVE><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of this vulnerability could allow a remote, unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code with elevated privileges.
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>10.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>9.0</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:F/RL:W/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>For some versions of Cisco AsyncOS Software for Cisco ESA and Cisco SMA, Telnet is configured on the Management port. Telnet services can be disabled to mitigate this vulnerability. Administrators can disable Telnet by using the administration graphical user interface (GUI) or by using the interfaceconfig command in the command-line interface (CLI). As a security best practice, customers should use Secure Shell (SSH) instead of Telnet.



Complete the following steps to disable Telnet via the GUI:



Step 1: Navigate to Network &gt; IP Interfaces &gt; interface_name.

Step 2: Remove the check from the box next to the Telnet service.

Step 3: Click on the Submit button to submit the change.

Step 4: Click the Commit Change button for these changes to take effect.



Use the interfaceconfig command, as shown in the example below to disable Telnet via the CLI.


ciscoesa&gt; interfaceconfig

Currently configured interfaces:
1. Data 1 (192.168.1.1/24 on Data1: mail3.example.com)
2. Data 2 (192.168.2.1/24 on Data2: mail3.example.com)
3. Management (192.168.42.42/24 on Management: mail3.example.com)

Choose the operation you want to perform:
- NEW - Create a new interface.
- EDIT - Modify an interface.
- GROUPS - Define interface groups.
- DELETE - Remove an interface.

[]&gt; edit
Enter the number of the interface you wish to edit.
[]&gt; 3

&lt;..output omitted&gt;

Do you want to enable Telnet on this interface? [N]&gt; N
Do you want to enable SSH on this interface? [N]&gt; Y

Note: The interfaceconfig command is described in detail in the section Other Tasks in the GUI in the Cisco AsyncOS Daily Management Guide available at the following link:

http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/security/esa/esa7.5/ESA_7.5_Daily_Management_Guide.pdf



Cisco AsyncOS Software for Cisco WSA has Telnet enabled by default; however once SSW is completed, telnet will be automatically disabled. 

The Cisco Applied Mitigation Bulletin (AMB) "Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Cisco IronPort Appliances Telnet Remote Code Execution Vulnerability", is available at ["http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/security/esa/esa7.5/ESA_7.5_Daily_Management_Guide.pdf"]http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120126-ironport["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120126-ironport"]
</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120126-ironport</URL><Description>Cisco IronPort Appliances Telnet Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>