<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco ASA Next-Generation Firewall Fragmented Traffic Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20130626-ngfw</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-06-26T14:13:36</Date><Description>Initial public release</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-06-26T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2013-06-26T14:13:36</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco ASA Next-Generation Firewall (NGFW) Services contains a Fragmented Traffic Denial of Service (DoS) vulnerability. 





Successful exploitation of this vulnerability on the Cisco ASA NGFW  could cause the device to reload or stop processing user traffic that has been redirected by the parent Cisco ASA to the ASA NGFW  module for further inspection.



There are no workarounds for this vulnerability, but mitigations are available.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130626-ngfw["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130626-ngfw"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130626-ngfw["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130626-ngfw"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-184514">Cisco ASA CX Context-Aware Security Software 9.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-184515">Cisco ASA CX Context-Aware Security Software 9.0.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-184688">Cisco ASA CX Context-Aware Security Software 9.0.1-40</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-184516">Cisco ASA CX Context-Aware Security Software 9.0.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-184689">Cisco ASA CX Context-Aware Security Software 9.0.2-68</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco ASA Next-Generation Firewall Fragmented Traffic Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCue88387</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in fragmented traffic processing on Cisco ASA NGFW could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a reload of the affected device.



The vulnerability is due to invalid parsing of reassembled packet data. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending fragmented traffic to be processed by one of the ASA NGFW deny policies.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2013-3382</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-184514</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-184515</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-184516</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-184688</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-184689</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability on the Cisco ASA NGFW appliance may cause the device to reload or stop processing user traffic.



Additionally, if the Cisco ASA with a Cisco ASA NGFW module running an affected version of software is configured in High-Availability mode (HA), a failover event may be triggered when the Cisco ASA NGFW reloads or stops forwarding traffic.



Repeated exploitation could result in a sustained failover condition of the parent Cisco ASA, and eventually lead to a sustained DoS condition.



</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.8</BaseScore><TemporalScore>6.8</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:H/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>
If the vulnerability has been exploited on the Cisco ASA NGFW and the traffic is interrupted, as a mitigation, the Modular Policy Framework (MPF) configuration on the Cisco ASA that is used to direct the user traffic toward the Cisco ASA NGFW can be removed. This will cause all user traffic to bypass Cisco ASA NGFW module inspection and allow it to pass through the Cisco ASA without inspection provided by the ASA NGFW.



The following example shows how to disable the redirecting of web traffic to the Cisco ASA NGFW module from the Cisco ASA firewall:





ASA(config)# policy-map cx_traffic_policy

ASA(config-pmap)# class cx_traffic

ASA(config-pmap-c)# no cxcs





Note: Cisco ASA can be configured with fail-open under MPF configuration. The fail-open keyword sets the Cisco ASA to allow all traffic through, uninspected, if the Cisco ASA NGFW module is unavailable.



Alternatively, fragmented traffic can be disallowed on the Cisco ASA firewall. This will cause the Cisco ASA firewall not to accept any fragments on its interfaces. Consequently, the Cisco ASA will not send any fragments to the Cisco ASA NGFW software module for inspection.



The following example shows how to disable processing of fragmented traffic on the Cisco ASA firewall:



ASA(config)# fragment chain 1 

Note: The above example will disable fragments on all the Cisco ASA interfaces. Fragmented traffic directed to and through the Cisco ASA will be dropped. Consequently, the Cisco ASA will not forward any fragmented traffic to the Cisco ASA NGFW or any of the configured modules.





</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>