<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco Prime Central for Hosted Collaboration Solution Assurance Excessive CPU Utilization Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20130227-hcs</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-02-27T15:48:41</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-02-27T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2013-02-27T15:48:41</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco Prime Central for Hosted Collaboration Solution (HCS) Assurance contains a vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition. Exploitation of this vulnerability could interrupt the monitoring of voice services.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-hcs["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-hcs"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security Intelligence Operations at the following link:



http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-hcs["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-hcs"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=28034</URL><Description>Identification and Mitigation of Vulnerabilities in Cisco Voice and Unified Communications Products</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-188692">Cisco Hosted Collaboration Solution 8.6(x) Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-189949">Cisco Hosted Collaboration Solution 8.6(2) Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-188694">Cisco Hosted Collaboration Solution 9.0(x) Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-189951">Cisco Hosted Collaboration Solution 9.0(1) Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Prime Central for Hosted Collaboration Solution Assurance Excessive CPU Utilization Issue</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuc07155</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Cisco Prime Central for HCS Assurance versions 8.6 and 9.0 contain a vulnerability
that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a DoS condition by consuming excessive CPU.



The vulnerability is triggered by malformed
TLS messages received by the system. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending
malformed TLS messages to TCP port 9043 or TCP port 9443. Successful exploit of the vulnerability could allow the
attacker to consume all available CPU cycles and interrupt the monitoring of voice services.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2013-1135</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-188692</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-188694</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-189949</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-189951</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of this vulnerability could cause a DoS condition and deny access to legitimate services.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.1</BaseScore><TemporalScore>5.9</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:M/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>No workarounds are available for this vulnerability.



Additional mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this Advisory:



http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=28034["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=28034"]</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>