<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>3.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-07-02T15:35:37</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.0</Number><Date>2014-07-08T21:14:32</Date><Description>Added information regarding fixed versions of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>3.0</Number><Date>2014-10-13T15:55:13</Date><Description>Added important information regarding fixed versions of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-07-02T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-10-13T15:55:13</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager (Cisco Unified CDM) is affected by the following vulnerabilities:


    Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability
    Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability 
    Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability 

Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability or of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability may allow an attacker
to execute arbitrary commands or obtain privileged access to the affected system.

Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability may allow an attacker to access and modify BVSMWeb portal user information
such settings in the personal phone directory, speed dials, Single Number Reach, and
call forward settings.



Cisco has released free software updates that address the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability and the
Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability. 

Cisco will provide a free software update for the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability as soon as the fix is available.



Workarounds that mitigate these vulnerabilities are not available. Customers that are concerned about the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability may apply the
mitigation detailed in the "Workarounds" section of this advisory. 



Note: Due to an error in the fix of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability, all Cisco Unified CDM Platform Software releases are
vulnerable regardless if a previous patch has been applied due to this security advisory. This advisory has been updated to provide additional information about the fix for the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability.





This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm</URL><Description>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689</URL><Description>Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201006">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager 8.1.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201007">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager 8.1.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201008">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager 8.1.3</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201009">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager 8.1.4</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201012">Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Platform VOSS platform 4.4.1</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCun49862</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the web framework of the
Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Application Software could allow an
authenticated, remote attacker to elevate privileges and gain
administrative access to the affected system.



The vulnerability
is due to improper implementation of authentication and authorization
controls of the Administration GUI. An attacker could exploit this
vulnerability by submitting a crafted URL to change the administrative credentials of a user.
The attacker needs to be authenticated to the system or convince a valid user of the Administration GUI to click a
malicious link.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-2197</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-201006</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201007</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201008</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability or of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability  may allow an attacker
to execute arbitrary commands
or obtain privileged access to the affected system.



Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability may allow an attacker to access and modify BVSMWeb portal user information
such settings in the personal phone directory, speed dials, Single Number Reach, and
call forward settings.  
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>9.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>7.4</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:S/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There are no workarounds that mitigate the vulnerabilities in this security advisory.



Customers that are affected by the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability should use the functionality offered by the Cisco Unified Communication Manager and the Cisco Unified CDM Self-Care portal instead of the Cisco Unified CDM BVSMWeb portal to provide services.



Additional mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this advisory: 

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689"]
</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm</URL><Description>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability><Vulnerability Ordinal="2" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCud41130</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="2">A vulnerability in the implementation of the framework that allows access to
support representatives of the Cisco
Unified Communications Domain Manager Platform Software could allow an unauthenticated,
remote attacker to connect to the affected system with the privileges of
the root user.



The vulnerability is due to the presence of
a default SSH private key, which is stored in an insecure way on the system. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by obtaining the SSH
private key. For example, the attacker might reverse engineer the binary file of the operating system.
This will allow the attacker to connect by using the support account to the
system without requiring any form of authentication. An exploit could allow the attacker to gain access to the system with the privileges of the root user.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-2198</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-201012</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability or of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability  may allow an attacker
to execute arbitrary commands
or obtain privileged access to the affected system.



Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability may allow an attacker to access and modify BVSMWeb portal user information
such settings in the personal phone directory, speed dials, Single Number Reach, and
call forward settings.  
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>10.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>8.7</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:H/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There are no workarounds that mitigate the vulnerabilities in this security advisory.



Customers that are affected by the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability should use the functionality offered by the Cisco Unified Communication Manager and the Cisco Unified CDM Self-Care portal instead of the Cisco Unified CDM BVSMWeb portal to provide services.



Additional mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this advisory: 

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689"]
</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm</URL><Description>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability><Vulnerability Ordinal="3" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCum77041</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="3">A vulnerability in the web framework of Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Application Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to access and modify BVSMWeb portal user information such as settings in the personal phone directory, speed dials, Single Number Reach, and call forward settings.



The vulnerability is due to improper implementation of authentication and authorization controls when accessing some web pages of the BVSMWeb portal. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by submitting a crafted URL to the affected system.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-3300</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-201006</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201007</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201008</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201009</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Privilege Escalation Vulnerability or of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager Default SSH Key Vulnerability  may allow an attacker
to execute arbitrary commands
or obtain privileged access to the affected system.



Successful exploitation of the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability may allow an attacker to access and modify BVSMWeb portal user information
such settings in the personal phone directory, speed dials, Single Number Reach, and
call forward settings.  
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.5</BaseScore><TemporalScore>7.1</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:P/I:P/A:P/E:F/RL:U/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There are no workarounds that mitigate the vulnerabilities in this security advisory.



Customers that are affected by the Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager BVSMWeb Unauthorized Data Manipulation Vulnerability should use the functionality offered by the Cisco Unified Communication Manager and the Cisco Unified CDM Self-Care portal instead of the Cisco Unified CDM BVSMWeb portal to provide services.



Additional mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this advisory: 

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=34689"]
</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140702-cucdm</URL><Description>Multiple Vulnerabilities in Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>