<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS XR Software Route Processor Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20120530-iosxr</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>2.1</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2012-05-30T14:41:02</Date><Description>Initial public release</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2012-05-31T20:12:22</Date><Description>Updated Software Versions and Fixes to clarify SMU names and to provide links to relevant Software Downloads pages</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.0</Number><Date>2012-08-14T19:59:58</Date><Description>Updated affected platforms to include RSP-4G and RSP-8G on ASR 9000 Series, prior to IOS XR 4.2.0</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.1</Number><Date>2012-08-23T20:37:09</Date><Description>Doc updated to correct first published date</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2012-05-30T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2012-08-23T20:37:09</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco IOS XR Software contains a vulnerability when handling crafted packets that may result in a denial of service condition. The vulnerability only exists on Cisco 9000 Series Aggregation Services Routers (ASR) Route Switch Processor (RSP-4G and RSP-8G), Route Switch Processor 440 (RSP440), and Cisco Carrier Routing System (CRS) Performance Route Processor (PRP). The vulnerability is a result of improper handling of crafted packets and could cause the route processor, which processes the packets, to be unable to transmit packets to the fabric.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120530-iosxr["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120530-iosxr"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security Intelligence Operations at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120530-iosxr["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120530-iosxr"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-109764">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.0.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-116017">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.0.3</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-116081">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.0.4</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-109769">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.1.0</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-116015">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.1.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-116016">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.1.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-116014">Cisco IOS XR Software 4.2 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree></cvrfdoc>