<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Blade Servers Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20140908-ucse</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-09-08T15:10:47</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-09-08T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-09-08T15:10:47</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Cisco Integrated Management Controller (Cisco IMC) SSH module of the Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Blade servers could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service condition.



The vulnerability is due to a failure to properly handle a crafted SSH packet. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted packet to the SSH server running on the Cisco IMC of an affected device, which could result in the Cisco IMC becoming unresponsive. The operating system running on the blade will be unaffected.

Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability

This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:



http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following email addresses:

    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    fulldisclosure@seclists.org 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.



For instructions on obtaining future documents or related content, please refer to Receiving Security Vulnerability Information from Cisco["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html#rsvifc"] in the Security Vulnerability Policy["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"].</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse</URL><Description>Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Blade Servers Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=35308</URL><Description>Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=35588</URL><Description>Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201972">Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Software (UCSE) 1.0.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201974">Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Software (UCSE) 1.0.2 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201976">Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Software (UCSE) 2.1.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-201978">Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Software (UCSE) 2.2.2 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuo69206</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Cisco Integrated Management Controller (Cisco IMC) SSH module of the Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Blade servers could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service condition.



The vulnerability is due to a failure to properly handle a crafted SSH packet. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted packet to the SSH server running on the Cisco IMC of an affected device, which could result in the Cisco IMC becoming unresponsive. The operating system running on the blade will be unaffected.
</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-3348</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-201972</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201974</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201976</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-201978</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may cause the Cisco IMC of the affected blade server to become unresponsive. This will result in the administrator being unable to utilize the out-of-band features that the Cisco IMC provides, such as remote power-on/off, IP keyboard-video-mouse (KVM), remote media (vMedia), and serial console access. The device may need to be physically restarted to restore the Cisco IMC functionality.



If the Cisco IMC of a blade server is affected by this vulnerability the OS or hypervisor running on the blade will remain unaffected. If a restart of the device is required to restore Cisco IMC functionality, Cisco recommends that administrators properly shutdown the OS prior to taking any restoration actions if possible; power will be lost to both the Cisco IMC and OS running on the blade.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.8</BaseScore><TemporalScore>6.4</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>No workarounds are available.



Additional mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Mitigation Bulletin companion document for this advisory, which is available at the following link: http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=35308["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=35308"]</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140908-ucse</URL><Description>Cisco Unified Computing System E-Series Blade Servers Cisco Integrated Management Controller SSH Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>