<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliance Clientless VPN ActiveX Control Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20120314-asaclient</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.1</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2012-03-14T15:52:16</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2012-05-15T14:43:56</Date><Description>Added information about the Microsoft Global Kill Bit update release on May 8th, 2012</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2012-03-14T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2012-05-15T14:43:56</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">The Cisco Clientless VPN solution as deployed by Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances (Cisco ASA) uses an ActiveX control on client systems to perform port forwarding operations. Microsoft Windows-based systems that are running Internet Explorer or another browser that supports Microsoft ActiveX technology may be affected if the system has ever connected to a device that is running the Cisco Clientless VPN solution. A remote, unauthenticated attacker who could convince a user to connect to a malicious web page could exploit this issue to execute arbitrary code on the affected machine with the privileges of the web browser.



The affected ActiveX control is distributed to endpoint systems by Cisco ASA.  However, the impact of successful exploitation of this vulnerability is to the endpoint system only and does not compromise Cisco ASA devices.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability.



Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are available.



This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120314-asaclient["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120314-asaclient"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120314-asaclient["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120314-asaclient"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120314-asaclient</URL><Description>Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliance Clientless VPN ActiveX Control Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-6588">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA)</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-32570">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 7.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-32571">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 7.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-32572">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 8.0</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-91007">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 8.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-32573">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 8.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-99995">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) .3</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-108070">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) .4</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-115267">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances Firmware (ASA) 8.6</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Clientless VPN Port Forwarder ActiveX Control Remote Code Execution Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCtr00165</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">The Cisco Clientless VPN solution as deployed by Cisco ASA 5500 Series Adaptive Security Appliances (Cisco ASA) uses an ActiveX control on client systems to perform port forwarding operations. Microsoft Windows-based systems that are running Internet Explorer or another browser that supports Microsoft ActiveX technology may be affected if the system has ever connected to a device that is running the Cisco Clientless VPN solution. A remote, unauthenticated attacker who could convince a user to connect to a malicious web page could exploit this issue to execute arbitrary code on the affected machine with the privileges of the web browser.



The affected ActiveX control is distributed to endpoint systems by Cisco ASA.  However, the impact of successful exploitation of this vulnerability is to the endpoint system only and does not compromise Cisco ASA devices.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2012-0358</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-6588</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-32570</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-32571</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-32572</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-32573</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-91007</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-99995</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-108070</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-115267</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may allow a remote, unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code on the affected end-user system with the privileges of the user who invoked the web browser.  If the user has administrative privileges, code execution may result in a complete compromise of the affected system.
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>9.3</BaseScore><TemporalScore>7.7</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:M/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>End users or administrators may mitigate Internet Explorer as an attack vector by setting the kill bit for the affected ActiveX control.  This can be achieved by modifying the registry either directly on the affected machine or via an Active Directory Group Policy.  

Warning: Incorrectly modifying the system registry of a Microsoft Windows-based device may cause serious problems.  Neither Cisco nor Microsoft can guarantee that you can resolve problems that may result from improper registry modification from either applying the registry changes via a .reg file or by using the Registry Editor incorrectly.  Modify the registry of your system at your own risk. 

To set the kill bit for the CLSID with a value of {B8E73359-3422-4384-8D27-4EA1B4C01232}, paste the following text in a text editor such as Notepad.  Save the file using the .reg filename extension.


Windows Registry Editor Version 5.00
[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Internet Explorer\ActiveX Compatibility\{B8E73359-3422-4384-8D27-4EA1B4C01232}]
"Compatibility Flags"=dword:04000400

[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Wow6432Node\Microsoft\Internet Explorer\ActiveX Compatibility\{B8E73359-3422-4384-8D27-4EA1B4C01232}]
"Compatibility Flags"=dword:04000400


End users can apply this .reg file to individual systems by double-clicking the file.  Administrators can also apply the registry change across domains by using Group Policy.  You can find more information about using Group Policy in the following Microsoft TechNet article: Group Policy Collection["http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=215719"]

When the registry change has been applied, Microsoft Internet Explorer must be restarted for the changes to take effect.  Once the kill bit has been set, the affected control will no longer be accessible by the Cisco Clientless VPN system or a malicious web page when accessed by Internet Explorer.  This change may impact some clientless installations that use the Cisco Port Forwarder ActiveX control. One common component that may stop operating is the ActiveX RDP plug-in.

 

Mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices in a network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this advisory: http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120314-asaclient["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120314-asaclient"]



Note:  When the updated ActiveX Control or the Microsoft Kill Bit update is applied to an endpoint device, the kill bit value in the registry will be changed to 0x00000400 from 0x04000400 if the above workaround has been applied.  This change still effectively blocks the execution of the affected ActiveX control.  The above registry change also sets the binary behaviors kill bit as well as the ActiveX kill bit.  The binary behaviors kill bit is supported on Windows Server 2003 and above, and potentially provides additional protections.  Platforms that do not support the binary behaviors kill bit will ignore this setting and only utilize the ActiveX portion of the bit-mask.
</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>