<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco Unified Presence Server Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20130227-cups</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.1</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-02-27T15:33:18</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2013-02-28T13:25:43</Date><Description>Corrected affected and fixed versions</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-02-27T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2013-02-28T13:25:43</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco Unified Presence Server (CUPS) contains a vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition on an affected device. Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. A workaround is available to mitigate this vulnerability. This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-cups["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-cups"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:



http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-cups["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130227-cups"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAMBAlert.x?alertId=28034</URL><Description>Identification and Mitigation of Vulnerabilities in Cisco Voice and Unified Communications Products</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-188007">Cisco Unified Presence Server  8.6.4</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-189786">Cisco Unified Communications Manager IM and Presence Service 9.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-189788">Cisco Unified Communications Manager IM and Presence Service 9.1 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco Unified Presence Server  Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCua89930</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Cisco Unified Presence Server (CUPS) contains a vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause a denial of service condition against the affected device.  An attacker could exploit this issue by sending a packet flood to the ESP port resulting in an increase in CPU utilization which could lead to a disruption of services.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2013-1137</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-188007</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-189786</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-189788</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may cause high CPU utilization that may lead to a DoS condition.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.8</BaseScore><TemporalScore>6.4</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>Filtering traffic from untrusted sources on TCP port 5060 can provide a workaround for this vulnerability.</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>