<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco TelePresence Supervisor MSE 8050 Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20130515-mse</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-05-15T15:11:11</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-05-15T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2013-05-15T15:11:11</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco TelePresence Supervisor MSE 8050 contains a vulnerability that may allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause high CPU utilization and a reload of the affected system.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are not available.



This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130515-mse["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130515-mse"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:



http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130515-mse["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20130515-mse"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses:

    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.</DocumentDistribution><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-191937">Cisco TelePresence Supervisor MSE 8050 Software 2.2 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco TelePresence Supervisor MSE 8050 Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuf76076</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in  the network stack of the Cisco TelePresence MSE 8050
Supervisor could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause high
CPU utilization and a reload of the affected system.



The vulnerability is
due to improper handling and processing of TCP connection requests sent at
a high rate. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending
a sequence of TCP segments at a high rate to the management IP address
of the affected system. A full TCP three-way handshake is required to exploit this vulnerability. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause high CPU utilization, which may trigger a reload of the affected system and cause a denial of service condition.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2013-1236</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-191937</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause high CPU utilization and a reload of the affected system.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.8</BaseScore><TemporalScore>6.4</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are not available.</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>