<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Der Spiegel Article on Networking Equipment Infiltration</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Response</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sr-20131229-der-spiegel</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>2.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-12-29T19:16:42</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2013-12-30T17:38:26</Date><Description>Updated the response as more specific details about the allegedly affected Cisco platforms was disclosed.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.2</Number><Date>2013-12-30T23:25:57</Date><Description>Updated the Cisco Response section to clarify that the article does not discuss or disclose any specific vulnerabilities.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>2.0</Number><Date>2014-03-13T18:56:13</Date><Description>Cisco PSIRT investigation closure.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-12-29T19:17:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-03-13T18:56:13</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="1">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityResponse/cisco-sr-20131229-der-spiegel</URL><Description>Der Spiegel Article on Networking Equipment Infiltration</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences></cvrfdoc>