<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>OpenSSL Heartbeat Extension Vulnerability in Multiple Cisco Products</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed</ID></Identification><Status>Interim</Status><Version>1.26</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-04-09T02:52:14</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2014-04-10T00:39:31</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.2</Number><Date>2014-04-10T21:42:34</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.3</Number><Date>2014-04-11T20:28:44</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.4</Number><Date>2014-04-12T22:09:18</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Software Versions and Fixes sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.5</Number><Date>2014-04-13T20:51:32</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, Details, and Software Versions and Fixes sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.6</Number><Date>2014-04-14T21:20:02</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, Workarounds, and Software Versions and Fixes sections. Alphabetized product lists.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.7</Number><Date>2014-04-15T22:48:14</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections. Cisco IP Video Phone E20 marked as not vulnerable. Cisco Prime Security Manager needs further investigation.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.8</Number><Date>2014-04-16T19:53:40</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, Workarounds, and Software Versions and Fixes sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.9</Number><Date>2014-04-17T21:06:44</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.10</Number><Date>2014-04-18T18:38:52</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Software Versions and Fixes sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.11</Number><Date>2014-04-22T20:15:30</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, Details and Software Versions and Fixes sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.12</Number><Date>2014-04-23T18:38:41</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable. The Cisco Nexus 1000V Switch for VMware vSphere was moved to the Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable section.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.13</Number><Date>2014-04-24T18:01:53</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Details.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.14</Number><Date>2014-04-25T18:11:05</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Software Versions and Fixes.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.15</Number><Date>2014-04-28T23:51:34</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Details sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.16</Number><Date>2014-04-29T22:01:17</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.17</Number><Date>2014-04-30T19:36:21</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.18</Number><Date>2014-05-02T19:14:37</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Exploitation and Public Announcements sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.19</Number><Date>2014-05-06T19:25:18</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.20</Number><Date>2014-05-09T18:08:06</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections. The Cisco Partner Support Services service was moved to the Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable section.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.21</Number><Date>2014-05-15T17:36:05</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, and Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable sections. Upon further investigation the Cisco Edge 300 Digital Media Player was moved to the Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable section.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.22</Number><Date>2014-05-22T22:28:16</Date><Description>Updated the Affected Products, Vulnerable Products, Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable, and Details sections. Added the IOS XE 3.12.0aS release to the list of vulnerable ones.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.23</Number><Date>2014-05-23T16:47:53</Date><Description>Updated the Details section. Removed the IOS XE 3.12.0aS version from the vulnerable list as it has been rebuilt to incorporate the fix before the initial release of the target platform.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.24</Number><Date>2014-06-06T13:03:42</Date><Description>Updated the Vulnerable Products and Details sections. Explicitly addressed the Cupid attack.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.25</Number><Date>2014-10-09T20:16:45</Date><Description>Listed the newly released Cisco Unified Communications Domain Manager version 10.1(1) as vulnerable.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.26</Number><Date>2014-10-29T16:11:45</Date><Description>Corrected a formatting issue.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-04-09T03:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-10-29T16:11:45</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Multiple Cisco products incorporate a version of the OpenSSL package affected by a vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to retrieve memory in chunks of 64 kilobytes from a connected client or server.



The vulnerability is due to a missing bounds check in the handling of the Transport Layer Security (TLS) heartbeat extension. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by implementing a malicious TLS or Datagram Transport Layer Security (DTLS) client, if trying to exploit the vulnerability on an affected server, or a malicious TLS or DTLS server, if trying to exploit the vulnerability on an affected client. An exploit could send a specially crafted TLS or DTLS heartbeat packet to the connected client or server. An exploit could allow the attacker to disclose a limited portion of memory from a connected client or server for every heartbeat packet sent. The disclosed portions of memory could contain sensitive information that may include private keys and passwords.



Please note that the devices that are affected by this vulnerability are the devices acting as an SSL server terminating SSL connections or devices acting as an SSL Client initiating an SSL connection. Devices that are simply traversed by SSL traffic without terminating it are not affected.



This advisory will be updated as additional information becomes available. Cisco will release free software updates that address these vulnerabilities. Workarounds that mitigate these vulnerabilities may be available.
This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME. CISCO EXPECTS TO UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AS NEW INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security Intelligence Operations at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed"]



Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following email addresses:

    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed</URL><Description>OpenSSL Heartbeat Extension Vulnerability in Multiple Cisco Products</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=33695</URL><Description>OpenSSL TLS/DTLS Heartbeat Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-197129">Cisco TelePresence Video Communication Server (VCS) X7.2 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-197132">Cisco TelePresence Video Communication Server (VCS) X7.2.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-197133">Cisco TelePresence Video Communication Server (VCS) X7.2.2</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-197131">Cisco TelePresence Video Communication Server (VCS) X8.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-192802">Cisco Desktop Collaboration Experience DX650 Software 10.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-192803">Cisco Desktop Collaboration Experience DX650 Software 10.0(1)</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-195819">Cisco Unified IP Phones 9900 Series Firmware 9.4.1</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-194330">Cisco Unified IP Phone 8945 9.3 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-194331">Cisco Unified IP Phone 8945 9.3(2)</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>OpenSSL TLS/DTLS Heartbeat Information Disclosure Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCuo17488</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Transport Layer Security (TLS)/Datagram Transport Layer Security (DTLS) heartbeat functionality in OpenSSL used in multiple Cisco products could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to retrieve memory in chunks of 64 kilobytes from a connected client or server.



The vulnerability is due to a missing bounds check in the handling of the TLS heartbeat extension. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by implementing a malicious TLS or DTLS client, if trying to exploit the vulnerability on an affected server, or a malicious TLS or DTLS server, if trying to exploit the vulnerability on an affected client. The attacker could then send a specially-crafted TLS or DTLS heartbeat packet to the connected client or server. An exploit could allow the attacker to disclose a limited portion of memory from a connected client or server for every heartbeat packet sent. The disclosed portions of memory could contain sensitive information that may include private keys and passwords.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-0160</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-192802</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-192803</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-194330</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-194331</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-195819</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-197129</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-197131</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-197132</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-197133</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>The impact of this vulnerability on Cisco products varies depending on the affected product. Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may cause portions of memory from a client or server to be disclosed. Note that the disclosed portions of memory could potentially include sensitive information such as private keys.</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>5.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>5.0</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:P/I:N/A:N/E:H/RL:U/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet><ScoreSet><BaseScore>5.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>4.1</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:P/I:N/A:N/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>Cisco has published an Event Response for this vulnerability:

http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/intelligence/ERP-Heartbleed.html["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/intelligence/ERP-Heartbleed.html"]</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140409-heartbleed</URL><Description>OpenSSL Heartbeat Extension Vulnerability in Multiple Cisco Products</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>