<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway D-Channel Denial of Service Vulnerability</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2014-01-22T15:58:56</Date><Description>Initial public release</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2014-01-22T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2014-01-22T15:58:56</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway contains a vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to trigger the drop of the data channel (D-channel),
causing all calls to be terminated and preventing users from making new
calls.



Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability. No workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are available.
This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw"]</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw</URL><Description>Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway D-Channel Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewAlert.x?alertId=32460</URL><Description>Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway D-channel Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196517">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.0 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196519">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.1 Base</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196522">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.1(1.43)</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196523">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.1(1.49)</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196524">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.1(1.56)</FullProductName><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-196521">Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW 3241 2.2 Base</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco TelePresence ISDN GW D-channel Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCui50360</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the code handling the ISDN Q.931 signaling
protocol  of the Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway could allow an
unauthenticated, remote attacker to trigger a drop of the data channel (D-channel),
causing all calls to be terminated and preventing users from making new
calls.



The vulnerability is due to improper handling of a crafted
Q.931 STATUS message. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by
injecting crafted packets in the Q.931 flow. An successful exploit could allow
the attacker to trigger a drop of the D-channel. As a result, all active calls handled by the affected
system will be terminated and it will not be possible to establish new calls until the D-channel
communication is restored. A software reload is necessary to restore normal behavior.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2014-0660</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-196517</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-196519</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-196521</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-196522</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-196523</ProductID><ProductID>CVRFPID-196524</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability may cause a drop of the ISDN D-channel which will cause all active calls to be dropped. Additionally, new calls will not be possible until the affected system is reloaded.
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>7.1</BaseScore><TemporalScore>5.9</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:M/Au:N/C:N/I:N/A:C/E:F/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>There is no workaround that mitigates this vulnerability.</Description></Remediation></Remediations><References><Reference Type="Self"><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20140122-isdngw</URL><Description>Cisco TelePresence ISDN Gateway D-Channel Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description></Reference></References></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>