<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco IP Video Phone E20 Default Root Account</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sa-20120118-te</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.0</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2012-01-18T15:53:24</Date><Description>Initial Public Release</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2012-01-18T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2012-01-18T15:53:24</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Summary" Type="General" Ordinal="1">Cisco TelePresence Software version TE 4.1.0 contains a default account vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to take complete control of the affected device.



The vulnerability is due to an architectural change that was made in the way the system maintains administrative accounts.  During the process of upgrading a Cisco IP Video Phone E20 device to TE 4.1.0, an unsecured default account may be introduced.  An attacker who is able to take advantage of this vulnerability could log in to the device as the root user and perform arbitrary actions with elevated privileges.





Cisco has released free software updates that address this vulnerability.



Workarounds that mitigate this vulnerability are available.



This advisory is available at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120118-te["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120118-te"]
</Note><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="2">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><DocumentDistribution>This advisory is posted on Cisco Security at the following link:

http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120118-te["http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20120118-te"]

Additionally, a text version of this advisory is clear signed with the Cisco PSIRT PGP key and circulated among the following e-mail addresses: 


    cust-security-announce@cisco.com 
    first-bulletins@lists.first.org 
    bugtraq@securityfocus.com 
    vulnwatch@vulnwatch.org 
    cisco@spot.colorado.edu 
    cisco-nsp@puck.nether.net 
    full-disclosure@lists.grok.org.uk 

Future updates of this advisory, if any, will reside on Cisco.com but may not be announced on mailing lists. Users can monitor this advisory's URL for any updates.
</DocumentDistribution><DocumentReferences><Reference><URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120118-te</URL><Description>Identifying and Mitigating Exploitation of the Cisco IP Video Phone E20 Default Root Account</Description></Reference></DocumentReferences><ProductTree xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/prod/1.1"><FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-113643">Cisco Telepresence TE4.4.4</FullProductName></ProductTree><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco TelePresence TE Software Default Root Account Vulnerability</Title><ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCtw69889</ID><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Cisco TelePresence Software version TE 4.1.0 contains a default account vulnerability that could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to take complete control of the affected device.



The vulnerability is due to an architectural change that was made in the way the system maintains administrative accounts.  During the process of upgrading a Cisco IP Video Phone E20 device to TE 4.1.0, an unsecured default account may be introduced.  An attacker who is able to take advantage of this vulnerability could log in to the device as the root user and perform arbitrary actions with elevated privileges.</Note></Notes><CVE>CVE-2011-4659</CVE><ProductStatuses><Status Type="Known Affected"><ProductID>CVRFPID-113643</ProductID></Status></ProductStatuses><Threats><Threat Type="Impact"><Description>Successful exploitation of the vulnerability could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to gain root access to the affected device.  This could allow the attacker to take arbitrary actions on the device with elevated privileges.
</Description></Threat></Threats><CVSSScoreSets><ScoreSet><BaseScore>10.0</BaseScore><TemporalScore>8.7</TemporalScore><Vector>AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:C/I:C/A:C/E:H/RL:OF/RC:C/</Vector></ScoreSet></CVSSScoreSets><Remediations><Remediation Type="Workaround"><Description>Administrators are advised to reset both the admin and root passwords with the following commands:



Reset Root User Password: 
rootsettings on  



Reset Admin User Password: 
xcommand systemunit adminpassword set password: 
Mitigations that can be deployed on Cisco devices within the network are available in the Cisco Applied Intelligence companion document for this advisory: http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoAppliedMitigationBulletin/cisco-amb-20120118-te

</Description></Remediation></Remediations></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>