<?xml version="1.0"?><cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/cvrf/1.1"><DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS and Cisco IOS XE Type 4 Passwords Issue</DocumentTitle><DocumentType>Cisco Security Response</DocumentType><DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor"><ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</ContactDetails><IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</IssuingAuthority></DocumentPublisher><DocumentTracking><Identification><ID>cisco-sr-20130318-type4</ID></Identification><Status>Final</Status><Version>1.1</Version><RevisionHistory><Revision><Number>1.0</Number><Date>2013-03-18T15:57:44</Date><Description>Initial public release.</Description></Revision><Revision><Number>1.1</Number><Date>2013-03-22T18:47:54</Date><Description>Added Bug ID and table of affected releases.</Description></Revision></RevisionHistory><InitialReleaseDate>2013-03-18T16:00:00</InitialReleaseDate><CurrentReleaseDate>2013-03-22T18:47:54</CurrentReleaseDate><Generator><Engine>TVCE</Engine></Generator></DocumentTracking><DocumentNotes><Note Title="Status of this Notice" Type="General" Ordinal="1">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A stand-alone copy or Paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL in the following section is an uncontrolled copy, and may lack important information or contain factual errors.
</Note></DocumentNotes><Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://www.icasi.org/CVRF/schema/vuln/1.1"><Title>Cisco IOS and Cisco IOS XE Type 4 Passwords Issue</Title><Notes><Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Cisco IOS and Cisco IOS XE devices contain an issue that could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to access sensitive information on a targeted device.



The issue is due to an implementation flaw in the affected software. The affected software implements an algorithm to hash user-provided plaintext passwords. This algorithm is called Type 4, and a password hashed using this algorithm is referred to as a Type 4 password. The algorithm design called for using Password-Based Key Derivation Function version 2 (PBKDF2), as described in RFC 2898 section 5.1, with the following input values:


     Hash algorithm = SHA-256
     Password = the user-provided plaintext password
     Salt = 80 bits (generated by calling a cryptographically secure random number generator)
     Iteration count = 1,000 (one thousand)

Due to an implementation issue, the Type 4 password algorithm does not use PBKDF2 and does not use a salt, but instead performs a single iteration of SHA-256 over the user-provided plaintext password. This approach causes a Type 4 password to be less resilient to brute-force attacks. 



These issues do not apply to devices running a Cisco IOS or Cisco IOS XE release without support for Type 4 passwords.



An authenticated, remote attacker could exploit the issue by logging in to an affected device and performing a brute-force attack. A successful attack could allow the attacker to access sensitive information on a targeted device.</Note></Notes></Vulnerability></cvrfdoc>